Philip Cadigan

617.429.0779 / phil@inkhorn.org / @pcad

Summary

I'm a software developer who loves to prototype, code, and release. I've tried at every stage of my career to dive into the subject at hand. For the past 10+ years that subject has been programming in the browser.

Technical Skills

JavaScript CSS HTML Java Python Performance Analysis PostgreSQL MySQL Solr/Lucene *NIX HTTP(S)? VCS

Work Experience

Engineering Interface Manager

lifeIMAGE

June 2014 - Present

Player/coach for the UI team.

- Work with executive, managerial, and individual contributors to craft professional interfaces.
- Serve the UI team to make sure projects run smoothly and employee happiness is a front and center focus.
- Regularly meet with direct reports to identify upcoming challenges and address on-going work.
- · Coordinate with stakeholders outside of engineering to insure that issues are recognized and goals are met.
- Champion efforts to improve software quality; including process discussion, automated testing, and improved documentation.
- Listen.
- Present responsibilities include the continuation of responsibilities as Software Engineer

Software Engineer, UI

lifelMAGE

April 2009 - May 2014

UI lead for multiple web-applications that aid the secure sharing of medical imaging.

- Design, build, and service single page web-apps using progressive methodologies (<u>AMD</u>, <u>Dependency Injection</u>, <u>Promises</u>, Comet, etc.) while still supporting legacy browsers.
- Work closely with Product Management and Quality Assurance to produce a final product that meets or exceeds
 users needs.
- Design and develop REST APIs that serve multiple client platforms (HTML/JS, .NET, iOS).
- Implement stringent security requirements that enable the proper sharing of medical data.
- Analyze performance metrics across multiple browser platforms; identifying areas for optimization and refactoring.
- Integrate web-apps with native frameworks (.NET and Cocoa) and plugins (Java and Flash) to extend the capabilities of our applications as needed.
- Create and maintain build processes (Ant and Maven) to produce optimized JavaScript and Flash artifacts.
- Implement <u>automated testing</u> in conjunction with continuous integration.
- Develop in-house tools that aid software engineering in the areas of performance and automation.
- Develop UI test-harnesses to aid a rapid "code and test" cycle.
- Perform the duties of scrum master, rescue stuck/blocked colleagues, and ensure the timely delivery of software.
- Interview candidates for technical and cultural fits within the organization.
- · Bring up to speed junior and senior candidates on concepts and frameworks used in the UI.
- Investigate and implement unit testing frameworks (buster.is and isUnit) to exercise client code.

• Keep up-to-date with industry trends and try to incorporate them wherever they make sense.

Software Engineer

Lycos Inc.

July 2007 to February 2009

Member of an agile web-development team tasked with creating new products utilizing emerging technologies. Participated in multiple phases of the software life cycle, including: brainstorming, requirements gathering, prototyping, development, usability, marketing, and usage analysis.

- Designed and wrote extensive back-end and front-end code for Lycos Cinema, a web application that allows users
 to synchronously watch videos and chat from within their browser. Worked closely with product management and
 design team to identify and fix usability issues.
- Successfully led programming team in a complete refactor of an internal RESTful web-service. This project consisted of overhauling tens of thousands of lines of back-end code, made heavy use of automated testing, and provided a clear and consistent interface for consumers of the data.
- Implemented scalable AJAX front-end for Lycos MIX, a site that allows users to build video playlists.
- Refactored existing web-scraping scripts for Lycos MIX into an easily extensible API, allowing new video providers to be dropped into place with zero configuration.
- Designed and implemented memcached-based caching system for Lycos Cinema, providing service and statistical monitoring, and transparent invalidation mechanisms.
- Interviewed and mentored graduate students in the Lycos Internship Program.
- Participated in training emphasizing: communication, team building, conflict resolution, and innovation.
- · Performed front-end performance audits for Lycos properties.
- Lead developer for a complete overhaul of Sparkcast, a peer-to-peer video broadcasting service. Sparkcast utilized a unique infrastructure designed to service both desktop and web-based clients. Portions of the service were written in C, Java, and PHP.
- · Architected testing framework for Lycos Cinema emphasizing: unit, integration, and automated browser testing.
- Led weekly engineering meeting. This meeting was the main forum for: redressing recurring technical issues, formulating standards for code quality, and evaluating new technologies.
- Received the runner-up prize in the Lycos Innovation Challenge for 'Bubblr' a collaborative RSS aggregator.

Co-Founder and Lead Developer

PbType LLC

April 2005 to May 2007.

Co-created a web-consultancy and development company specializing in standards compliant web development. As co-founder I was intimately involved in all aspects of the business from strategic thinking to procuring office supplies.

- Led programming on all major projects. Managed programming life cycle, including but not limited to: design, prototyping, development, testing, and implementation.
- Managed and developed client relationships, including: needs assessment, project estimation, updates, acceptance testing, and post-delivery wrap-up.
- Created and coordinated marketing efforts for the company including: press releases, blog, printed materials, and take-aways.
- Coordinated legal negotiations for company including incorporation, intellectual property arrangements, and contracts.
- Designed, planned, and implemented rPapers. rPapers was a Django-based web 2.0 service offering tools to help people share their research.
- Implemented version control system (Subversion) and bug tracking database (Trac) to keep code-base manageable across multiple developers and environments.
- Researched and maintained knowledge of relevant emerging technologies.
- Provided clients with advice and code to enhance search engine rankings.
- Implemented ratified standards and APIs to increase data portability and interoperability.

Journals Internet Marketing Manager

The MIT Press

April 2001 to April 2005

- Co-managed a high traffic web-catalog receiving 130,000 unique visits per month.
- Led a complete rewrite and redesign of the web-catalog, coordinating a team of freelance designers, programmers, and in-house committees.
- Created and implemented ongoing development projects (e.g., e-mail lists, stats, discounts) to enhance and ensure the quality and currency of our web-catalog.
- Oversaw web-production schedule for 35 journals; including timely and accurate publication of new content, posting sample articles, verifying properly editorial information, and pricing.
- Fostered reader involvement through increased access, e-mail alerts, sample articles, and letters-to-the-editor module.
- Deployed strategies for e-journals. Coordinated with in-house design team, editors, programmers, and customer service on conceptual development, infrastructure, and policy.
- Served as primary contact with electronic publishing vendors, ensured operational efficiency and increased relevancy of services.
- Implemented with IT: hardware upgrades, disaster recovery, and security and network policies.
- Member of the Management Board Task Force for Digital Strategies.
- Recipient of the MIT Press 2001 Award for Efficiency and Cost Savings.

Journals Promotion Coordinator

The MIT Press

August 1999 to April 2001

Oversaw from start to finish the design, planning, and execution of direct mail campaigns for over 30 journals. Designed advertisements, brochures, and inserts for journals and direct mail promotions.

Membership Coordinator

WBUR 90.9 FM

February 1999 to August 1999

Created database and maintained financial records for over 40,000 donors, assisted volunteers, furnished customer service, copywrote promotional pieces.

Education

Bachelor of Arts: Philosophy/History 1993-2000

University of Massachusetts at Amherst

Graduate Courses in Computer Science

2007-Present

Harvard University: Extension School.

A collection of courses (Data Structures, Discrete Math, Calculus, AI, etc.) mostly belonging to a Computer Science Master's curriculum.